# Anila Nisar

571-390-3486 | Manassas, VA | developer.naaz@gmail.com | /anila-nisar/ | github.com/Anila277

#### Summary

Full Stack Software Engineer with an eye for detail and the ability to identify and solve complex problems analytically and critically. Effective planner who understands the full life cycle of web applications and able to create responsive websites utilizing frontend libraries and frameworks such as React and Bootstrap. Ability to approach each project with an open mind while keeping the user in mind to improve the overall experience.

### **Skills and Tools**

Javascript | React | MongoDB | HTML | CSS | Node.JS | Trello | Express | Bootstrap | Python | Django | EJS | PostgreSQL | Heroku | Netlify | Bash | Postman | JQuerry | NPMs | TypeScript

## **Software Development Projects**

August 2022 - Present

#### Is Funsy - Deployed App

- Designed a full stack web application called *Is Funsy* which allows users to search for gifs and random inspirational quotes.
- Utilized Ajax to call forth a third party API and displayed information based on user search queries.
- Applied a for-in-loop that checks the Giphy API data and appends each index of the data to our container class.
- Created an array that contains quotes and authors and used an math random function to randomly display a random quote.
- Technologies Used: JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Giphy API, Google Fonts. Deployed on GitHub. Fantasies: A Poetry Escape Deployed App
- Designed as a full stack MERN application, paired-programming with 2 Software developers, the site allows users to create an account and contribute by adding or commenting on existing poetry.
- Used trello to participate in agile styled meetings to complete one week sprints.
- Used figma to map out wireframes and flowcharts to show correlation between the UX and UI.
- Created intelligent routing with express.
- Technologies Used: Node.JS, MongoDB, React, Heroku, Netlify, Stands4 API, Vanilla CSS, GitHub. Deployed on Netlify. Pot-of-Flowers Deployed App
- Designed as a MEN application, the app is for a flower shop that allows the customers to choose the types of flowers and design their own pots.
- Inorder to keep our code clean and dry we used partials to build out a reusable block of codes.
- Implemented full CRUD functionality which allows a user to create, edit, and delete flowers. Incorporated this by creating forms that had different methods such as post and put.
- We stored web resources with MongoDB allowing for quick website load time.
- Technologies Used: Node.JS, MongoDB, Heroku, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Mongoose, Express

#### **Professional Experience**

## **Business Development Manager** Nisar Transportation, Manassas, VA

January 2009 - March 2015

- Oversaw the development of new service offerings based on detailed and documented insights of market and client needs, establishing a positive business rapport with external stakeholders and prospective clients.
- Managed carrier performances and Department of Transportations' regulations reporting and maintenance logs.

Caretaker August 2016 - Present

- Managed four children from the ages of 0-6, responsible for scheduling of educational, social skills and events.
- Encouraged understanding and positive self-concepts in children by supporting their emotional and social development.
- Communicated with children's parents regarding daily activities and behavioral problems and determined the best course of action

#### Education